JONATHAN KOLYER

SOFTWARE
DEVELOPMENT
PROFESSIONAL

CONTACT DETAILS

Location: San Francisco Phone: 415-699-2175

Email Github LinkedIn Resume

LANGUAGES

- TypeScript / Python
- Ruby / Java
- HTML / CSS
- SQL / GraphQL
- Swift / Objective-C

SOME TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

- Node.js / Next.js
- React / React Native
- FastAPI
- Rails
- PostgreSQL / Redis
- AWS
- Kubernetes
- FIK
- LangChain

PROFILE

Seasoned developer & leader over 25 years – specializing in pattern-based architectures solving business problems.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Technical Leadership

Process and project management. SDLC. Product strategy.

Management

Mentorship. Communications. Team experience. Bootstrapping.

Software Design & Implementation

Cloud microservices. Chatbots. Mobile. GitOps. Media processing. Monorepos. SaaS. LLM / RAG.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager

QuickNode, Inc.

June 2022 - July 2023

- Grew apps team from zero to twenty ICs with six direct reports.
- Managed monorepo infrastructure for a dozen applications.
- Built development cloud infrastructure on AWS.
- Built CI/CD pipeline for Kubernetes & ArgoCD.
- Initiated ELK observability and monitoring systems deployment.
- Prototyped content generation tools with ChatGPT/LangChain.

Principal / Founding Engineer

Chask.ai

September 2020 - June 2022

Developer of chatbot platform for group task management.

- Built conversational AI engine with administration portal and Slack integration.
- Implemented Rasa for NLP (pre-LLM), with React / MUI interface and NestJS / GraphQL backend.

Head of Solutions Engineering

Doc.ai

January 2019 - May 2020

Technical lead for mobile engagements with Anthem.

- Led team building SDK for conversational AI on iOS / Android.
- Designed state machine engine with JSON schema to navigate conversation tree.
- Oversaw development and communications with Anthem.

PROJECTS

Building <u>Goach.app</u> – a life goal coach, providing a goal fulfillment process using chat, data/media creation, and more. Tech stack is Next.js (TypeScript), FastAPI (Python), Supabase.

Mobile Architect - IOS

TextNow

May 2017 - August 2018

Designed new chat interface framework for <u>telephony & messaging</u> platform; introduced best practices and testing processes.

Founding Engineer

<u>JamKazam</u>

January 2013 - May 2018

Built a suite of applications for musicians to play together online.

Software Architect

PayNearMe

February 2014 - February 2017

Point-of-sale mobile and back-end applications.

Chief Technical Officer / Founding Engineer

PodOmatic

March 2005 – February 2013

Technical lead for podcasting social network wearing any hat necessary.

Previous Roles

1991 - 2013

- Actor represented by <u>Look Talent</u>
- SaleSorter CTO: retail sales aggregator start-up
- Bowstreet Solutions Architect: Cisco Systems engagement
- Moody's KMV Web Architect: Credit risk modeling
- Infoscape System Consultant: Java-based products
- Apple Consulting Engineer: On-site custom app development
- AT&T Wireless: Consulting engineer
- WhiteLight Systems: Lead developer
- NASA Ames: Research software engineer
- UC Berkeley: Research software engineer

EDUCATION

MS, Industrial Engineering & Operations Research University of California, Berkeley

1991

BA, Mathematics

Northwestern University

1987